A Guide to the Frank Richard Stockton Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #5866-a
Frank Richard Stockton Collection 1874-1898
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
5866-a
18 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit [ 1963 Dec 17 ] 1966 May 11
Item Listing
- Manuscript
  - The Merry Chanter, n. d.; AMsS, 88 p.
- Letters
  - Frank Richard Stockton to Rossiter Johnson, 1874 Jun 12; ALS, 1 p.
    [Informs him that [
    St. Nicholas
    ] accepted "Care of the Profits"; requests changes in the manuscript.]
  - Frank Richard Stockton to Mr. Smith, 1877 Feb 2; ALS, 1 p.
    [Informs him of his plans to travel in Virginia, further south, and to the Bahamas; gives him his Virginia address.]
  - Frank Richard Stockton to [Charles Kirk ?] Munroe, 1880 Jul 13; ALS, 3 p.
    [Says he can deliver a serial story in winter, at the earliest; says he is otherwise engaged at present; asks if this will suit him.]
  - [Charles Kirk ?] Munroe to Frank Richard Stockton, 1880 Jul 20; ALS, 1 p.
    [Replies to him on verso of ALS 1880 Jul 13; says he is happy to examine the serial at any time, he will pay $10 per 1000 words if the story is accepted.]
  - Frank Richard Stockton to William Henry Rideing, 1887 Jan 23; ALS, 2 p.
    [Says he will be happy to see him at his New York home any morning, he is ready to talk about his "Boyish days" at Rideing's suggestion; congratulates him on his impending wedding.]
  - Frank Richard Stockton to Charles Scribner's Sons, 1887 Jul 20; ALS, 1 p.
    [Informs the company that he has returned all the proofs of
    The Bee-Man of Orm
    except the map.]
  - Frank Richard Stockton to Frederick Abbot Stokes, 1891 May 26; ALS, 3 p.
    [Accepts honor of election as President of the Aldine Club; hopes to spend more time in New York next winter; requests list of the elected officers; voices appreciation.]
  - Frank Richard Stockton to Julius Chambers, 1892 Dec 29; TLS, 1 p.
    [Hopes to be able to write requested story for Chamber's paper within the next 6 months; says he is unable to promise the story, as he is very busy.]
  - Frank Richard Stockton to Clover Club, 1893 Jan 8; ANS, 1 p.
    [Writes in third person; accepts invitation to the anniversary dinner, January 19, 1893.]
  - Frank Richard Stockton to George [Riker] Bishop, 1893 Jan 11; ALS, 2 p.
    [Regrets that he and Mrs. Stockton are unable to dine with the [Unitarian ?] Club; thanks him for the complimentary proposition to speak in [
    American Literature
    ?].]
  - Frank Richard Stockton to A. A. Hill, 1895 Jul 6; ALS, 1 p.
    [Asks $400 for the American rights for a Christmas story; explains his terms (when selling all rights to one party, etc.) to him.]
  - Frank Richard Stockton to Robert Underwood Johnson, 1896 Sep 29; TLS, 1 p.
    [Refers to a meeting of the American Copyright League which he was unable to attend; favors proposed consolidation of the American Author's Guild with the Copyright League; mentions other matters regarding copyright.]
  - Frank Richard Stockton to William Henry Rideing, 1897 Feb 24; ALS, 1 p.
    [Explains that the manuscript of "
    My Doge
    " has been sent to Boston instead of to Rideing in New York. ]
  - ALS, 2 p.
    [Sends timetable of trains leaving from New York to Madison for Baxter's visit to Stockton in Convent Station, New Jersey the following week.]
  - Frank Richard Stockton to E. Leslie Gilliams, 1897 Oct 25; TLS, 1 p.
    [Discusses a letter and telegram from Gilliams as well as the visit of a representative, whom Stockton says never came, of Gilliams' monetary business, which has not been taken care of.]
  - Frank Richard Stockton to Julius Chambers, 1898 Dec 14; ALS, 2 p.
    [Wishes him success with his book; praises his storytelling; says the stories remind him of his own boyhood, he is convinced that the book will be enjoyed by boys of all ages.]